Sugar shocked.
因糖而震惊。
That describes the reaction of many Americans this week following revelations that, 50 years ago, the sugar industry paid Harvard scientists for research that shifted the focus away from sugar’s role in heart disease—and put the spotlight squarely on dietary fat.
这正是本周许多美国人在相关内幕曝光后的反应：50年前，制糖业曾出钱请哈佛大学的科学家做研究，这些研究把焦点从糖在心脏病中的作用上移开，转而将关注的中心直接放在了膳食脂肪上。
What might surprise consumers is just how many present-day nutrition studies are still funded by the food industry.
可能让消费者感到意外的是，时至今日，竟然仍有如此多的营养学研究由食品行业资助。
Nutrition scholar Marion Nestle of New York University spent a year informally tracking industry-funded studies on food.
纽约大学营养学学者玛丽恩·内斯特尔花了一年时间，以非正式的方式追踪由行业资助的食品研究。
“Roughly 90% of nearly 170 studies favored the sponsor’s interest,” Nestle tells us.
“在近170项研究中，约90%偏向资助方的利益，”内斯特尔告诉我们。
Other systematic reviews support her conclusions.
其他系统性综述也支持她的结论。
For instance, studies funded by Welch Foods—the brand behind Welch’s 100% Grape Juice—found that drinking Concord grape juice daily may boost brain function.
例如，韦尔奇食品公司（即韦尔奇100%葡萄汁背后的品牌）资助的研究发现，每天喝康科德葡萄汁可能会增强大脑功能。
Another, funded by Quaker Oats, concluded, as a Daily Mail story put it, that “hot oatmeal breakfast keeps you full for longer.”
另一项研究由桂格燕麦公司资助，用《每日邮报》一篇报道的话来说，其结论是“早餐吃热燕麦粥能让你饱得更久”。
Last year, The New York Times revealed how Coca-Cola was funding well-known scientists and organizations promoting a message that, in the battle against weight gain, people should pay more attention to exercise and less to what they eat and drink.
去年，《纽约时报》披露了可口可乐公司如何资助知名科学家和机构，而这些科学家和机构所宣扬的观点是：在与体重增加的斗争中，人们应该多关注运动，少关注自己吃什么、喝什么。
Coca-Cola also released data detailing its funding of several medical institutions and associations between 2010 and 2015.
可口可乐公司还公布了数据，详细列出了它在2010年至2015年间对几家医疗机构和协会的资助。
“It’s certainly a problem that so much research in nutrition and health is funded by industry,” says Bonnie Liebman, director of nutrition at the Center for Science in the Public Interest.
“营养与健康领域有这么多研究由产业界资助，这无疑是个问题，”公共利益科学中心营养部主任邦妮·利布曼说。
“When the food industry pays for research, it often gets what it pays for.”
“食品行业出钱资助研究时，往往是花钱买什么，就得到什么。”
And what it pays for is often a pro-industry finding.
而它花钱买的，往往是对该行业有利的研究发现。
Given this environment, consumers should be skeptical when reading the latest finding in nutrition science and ignore the latest study that pops up on their news feed.
鉴于这种状况，消费者在读到营养科学的最新发现时应该持怀疑态度，并对新闻推送里冒出来的最新研究置之不理。
“Rely on health experts who’ve reviewed all the evidence,” Liebman says, pointing to the official government Dietary Guidelines, which are based on reviews of hundreds of studies.
“要信赖那些审视过全部证据的健康专家，”利布曼说，并举政府官方的《膳食指南》为例，该指南以对数百项研究的综述为依据。
“And that expert advice remains pretty simple,” says Nestle.
“而专家给出的这些建议依然相当简单，”内斯特尔说。
“We know what healthy diets are—lots of vegetables, not too much junk food, balanced calories.
“我们知道健康的饮食是什么样的——多吃蔬菜，别吃太多垃圾食品，热量均衡。
Everything else is really difficult to do experimentally.”
除此之外的一切，都真的很难通过实验来研究。”